<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Mostly interesting stuff</title>
    <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com" />
    <updated>2025-03-22T19:04:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>panvicka</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.panvicka.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Buenos Aires Guide - part 3: Exchanging currency in Buenos Aires</title>
        <author>
            <name>panvicka</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-guide-part-3-exchanging-currency-in-buenos-aires/"/>
        <id>https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-guide-part-3-exchanging-currency-in-buenos-aires/</id>
            <category term="travel"/>
            <category term="Patagonia 2024/25"/>

        <updated>2025-03-22T17:59:12+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    So, if ATMs aren't reliable, where do you get cash? First the question - is cash necessary in Buenos Aires or Argentina/Patagonia? Not really, or at least not much, since credit/debit cards are accepted almost everywhere (even in very remote areas in Patagonia). However, you'll&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br>So, <a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-1-getting-of-the-airport/#atm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">if ATMs aren't reliable</a>, where do you get cash?</p>
<p>First the question - is cash necessary in Buenos Aires or Argentina/Patagonia? Not really, or at least not much, since credit/debit cards are accepted almost everywhere (even in very remote areas in Patagonia).</p>
<p>However, you'll pay less if you use cash in most restaurants and small shops (sometimes saving up to 20%!). If your trip is less than two weeks, you might pay slightly more to skip the hassle of getting cash. But since our adventure spanned two months, I was glad we often chose the cheaper cash option when reviewing my bank statements later.</p>
<p>What are the options to get Argentina Pesos in Argentina?</p>
<p>First, you can wire yourself money using Western Union. Your first transaction is fee-free, and you can use new emails to avoid fees entirely. This works well in BA, but small towns often run out of cash at WU locations, limit withdrawals to impractically low amounts like 50000 ARP, or require long waits.</p>
<p>Another option is a bit sketchy but worked well for us. Visit Florida Street in BA, where plenty of options exist to exchange Dollars or Euros for Pesos. The men (this job is rarely done by women) are impossible to miss. We asked for rates multiple times, picked the best, and followed the gentleman into a posh building. After a silent elevator ride and awkward chit-chat, we had our exchanged money—2 million pesos, mostly in 1000 ARP bills (yes, a literal brick of cash). It could have gone wrong, with us leaving without 2000 Dollars, but it worked and seems quite normal.</p>
<p id="pristine-bills">We brought 100 dollar and euro bills in pristine condition. I read smaller bills might be exchanged for less, but didn’t risk it. I also enjoyed the feeling of handling cash that felt like money coming from a very illegal source at least once in my otherwise boring life.</p>
<p>Life Hack for Kindle users: Store cash in the Kindle cover. We kept bills pristine for the shady exchange office this way.</p>
<p><br><span style="color: #e67e23;"><strong>Funny story:</strong> We kept 500 Euros in my Kindle cover, which I forgot about after returning from vacation. For weeks, I carried this ridiculous amount of cash, leaving it unattended several times. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Buenos Aires Guide - part 2: The hunt for a SIM in Buenos Aires</title>
        <author>
            <name>panvicka</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-2-the-hunt-for-a-sim-in-buenos-aires/"/>
        <id>https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-2-the-hunt-for-a-sim-in-buenos-aires/</id>
            <category term="travel"/>
            <category term="Patagonia 2024/25"/>

        <updated>2025-03-22T17:58:08+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    After getting from the airport, locating our hostel, showering, and refreshing, we set out to find a SIM card with internet. In my research, I learned that you need to activate the SIM card in Argentina. The online process is said to be a bit&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>After getting from the airport, locating our hostel, showering, and refreshing, we set out to find a SIM card with internet. In my research, I learned that you need to activate the SIM card in Argentina.</p>
<p>The online process is said to be a bit annoying since the site is not intuitive and difficult to navigate on a phone. It also takes time, as a real person reviews the application. Alternatively, visit a Claro (phone service provider in Argentina) location in person with your passport, and the activation takes just a few minutes.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e67e23;"><strong>Funny story:</strong> We landed in the middle of the night and were too early, so we waited in a nearby café. It was our first shock—avocado toast was 12000 ARP, and coffee was 4000 ARP. We thought it was just a pricey café. We could not been more wrong, turns out, things just got very expensive very quickly.</span></p>
<p>At 9:05, we entered the Claro shop and left a few seconds later. The security guide (likely annoyed) told us we needed the physical SIM card, which they didn’t sell. We found a kiosk with a Claro sticker and bought two SIM cards. (Buenos Aires has kiosks everywhere, but they vanish when you need one!)</p>
<p>We returned to Claro, activated our SIM cards smoothly, and purchased a 1-month bundle with about 8 GB. Compared to Central European costs, it was crazy cheap.</p>
<p><span style="color: #e67e23;"><strong>Funny story: </strong>We planned to stay for 2 months and thought, "We'll just buy another bundle when needed." Fast forward 30 days, we were in the middle of nowhere, traveling from Chile. Not the best time to run out of internet. I tried buying more GB online from Claro, but none of our cards worked... apparently, you need an Argentine credit card to top up. Thankfully, I discovered <a href="https://www.ding.com" style="color: #e67e23;">Ding</a>, which lets you add credits to almost any SIM Card. You’ll need the provider’s app or an account online to buy the internet packs with new money you top up using Ding, so do this beforehand!</span></p>
<h2>Troubleshooting the Claro SIM Card</h2>
<p>For my boyfriend, his SIM card worked immediately after restarting his phone (Google Pixel). Mine didn’t - no internet (Doggee). I had to create a new APN (Settings -&gt; Cellular networks -&gt; Access Point Names, or similar depending on your OS). Oddly, an APN was already there, but adding another identical one and selecting it worked. I found a similar solution later on Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProjectFi/comments/41rxpc/possible_fix_for_international_data_problems/">here</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Buenos Aires Guide - part 1: Getting from the Airport in Buenos Aires</title>
        <author>
            <name>panvicka</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-1-getting-of-the-airport/"/>
        <id>https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-1-getting-of-the-airport/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/3/IMG_0836.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="travel"/>
            <category term="Patagonia 2024/25"/>

        <updated>2025-03-22T17:29:39+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/3/IMG_0836.jpg" alt="Busy city with a lot of cars and big white obelist" />
                    <p>Congratulations, you survived your flight! So, what's next? Whatever your plans are, you'll need money, a bus card, and a SIM card with internet access.<br><br>I did my research before landing in Buenos Aires, but things change quickly, and I was a bit surprised by a few realities.<br><br>Here's what we planned for our first 24 hours in Argentina:<br><br>1. Survive the flight<br>2. Get to the hostel and take a shower after 24 hours of travel<br>3. Drop off our huge backpacks<br>4.<a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-2-the-hunt-for-a-sim-in-buenos-aires/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Head out to the city to buy SIM cards</a><br>5. <a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-guide-part-3-exchanging-currency-in-buenos-aires/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Exchange money</a><br>6. Battle jet lag</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/3/IMG_0836.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Busy city with a lot of cars and big white obelist" /></p>
                <p>Congratulations, you survived your flight! So, what's next? Whatever your plans are, you'll need money, a bus card, and a SIM card with internet access.<br><br>I did my research before landing in Buenos Aires, but things change quickly, and I was a bit surprised by a few realities.<br><br>Here's what we planned for our first 24 hours in Argentina:<br><br>1. Survive the flight<br>2. Get to the hostel and take a shower after 24 hours of travel<br>3. Drop off our huge backpacks<br>4.<a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-beginner-guide-part-2-the-hunt-for-a-sim-in-buenos-aires/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Head out to the city to buy SIM cards</a><br>5. <a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-guide-part-3-exchanging-currency-in-buenos-aires/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Exchange money</a><br>6. Battle jet lag</p>

<h2>Airport situation in BA</h2>
<p><br>Double check which airport your flight uses. Our international flight from São Paulo landed at the AEP (small and centrally located by the shore), while our domestic flight to Bariloche departed from the sprawling EZE (massive and situated on the outskirts, about 35 minutes from the tourist center of BA without traffic).<br><br>We found our bags without a hitch (not thanks to my nervous AirTag tracking at every chance as I imagine). Coming from a wealthy European country and looking very much like eager hikers, immigration was a breeze. However, we did have to present our accommodation booking for the night.</p>
<h3>Getting from AEP by Bus</h3>
<p><br>Like all airports, taxis are abundant outside. Too luxurious for two backpackers - let's take the bus!<br><br>There's a catch, though. You need a SUBE card to hop on a bus. It’s a chip card available at kiosks for 1700 ARP. Not a huge sum, but here's the snag – the airport kiosks wouldn’t sell us a SUBE card when we tried to pay with a card. Only cash was accepted. We had dollars, but only crisp, well-ironed 100-dollar bills (<a href="https://blog.panvicka.com/buenos-aires-guide-part-3-exchanging-currency-in-buenos-aires/#pristine-bills" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">what?</a>), which were useless in this scenario.</p>
<h3><svg class="li li-swords" width="24px" height="24px" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><g><path d="M14.5 17.5 3 6V3h3l11.5 11.5M13 19l6-6M16 16l4 4M19 21l2-2M14.5 6.5 18 3h3v3l-3.5 3.5M5 14l4 4M7 17l-3 3M3 19l2 2"/></g></svg> Unexpected Side Quest: Getting Money at AEP</h3>
<p><br>You're probably aware of Argentina's currency situation. If not let me offer you a short AI summary: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>ChatGPT: Over the past 20 years, Argentina has faced recurring financial crises, including hyperinflation and debt defaults. Hyperinflation peaked at over 3,000% in 1989 and reached 54% in 2019. This has led to high living costs for locals, unpredictable prices for tourists and difficulties in accessing cash due to high inflation and limited bank credit.</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="atm">Just use an ATM, right? Easier said than done. Before leaving, I read that ATMs often run out of money, malfunction, or charge exorbitant fees along with the official exchange rate. Sadly, I found all this to be true. <br><br>There are two ATMs at the airport. One was out of order, and the other charged a hefty 20% fee plus 5000 ARP. Using my Maestro card, I withdrew 20000 ARP, leaving 9000 ARP in fees behind—costing me 35 Euros [November 2024]. Quite a rip-off—I'd expect at least 35000 ARP for that amount.<br><br>We bought the SUBE card and tried topping it up at a kiosk (let's call it kiosk #1). The attendant (likely annoyed) directed us to another kiosk (#2) to use their machine for topping up. Unfortunately, the machine was out of service.<br><br><span style="color: #e67e23;"><strong>Funny story:</strong> The machine was full of money, awaiting someone to empty it. I suppose going from 100 ARP to 1000 ARP for the same bus ride over a few years challenges machinery specs.</span><br><br>Kiosk #2 couldn’t manually top up our cards, but the friendly lady called the guy at kiosk #1, who could do it manually. After another trek through the arrival hall, our cards were topped up. I wonder how many people just give up. I was this close to booking an Uber, but my wonderful boyfriend persisted.</p>
<h3>Bus Ride</h3>
<p><br>Public transport in Buenos Aires is impressive. The number of buses is staggering, and Google Maps does wonders for navigation, knowing all stations and routes.<br><br>Research your first bus ride while you still have internet access, as you can't buy or activate a SIM card at AEP (I was aware of the eSIMs for international travel but found them too expensive. It is probably a good choice if you visit for a week or so.)There was Wi-Fi, but it didn't work for us. Download an offline map, check the bus number you need. GPS will work without internet, but you should know your route.<br><br>As an introverted person without <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">fluent </span> any Spanish skills, I was nervous. After boarding the bus, you must tell the driver your destination. He'll quickly input it on his computer, and then you can tap your card. You can see the fare and your remaining balance.<br><br>We were unaware of this, and the driver (likely annoyed), charged us the highest fare possible (around 5000 ARP for a short 10-minute ride) as answer to your confused silence stares after getting on the bus. Lesson learned!<br><br><span style="color: #e67e23;"><strong>Funny Story:</strong> We often ran out of money on our SUBE card. Rides got pricey (8000 ARP sometimes wasn't enough for a day’s travel), and some kiosks with "old software" wouldn't top up more than 10000 ARP. Twice, we were stranded in villages with no way to top up. The bus driver didn’t accept cash. Both times, we asked people at the bus stop to pay for us, reimbursing them with cash. Topping up the card with mobile app is sadly reserved only for those with Argentine ID.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Add a Kindle Dictionary: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
        <author>
            <name>panvicka</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.panvicka.com/adding-a-dictionary-to-kindle/"/>
        <id>https://blog.panvicka.com/adding-a-dictionary-to-kindle/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/IMG_2642.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="tech"/>

        <updated>2025-03-10T12:52:26+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/IMG_2642.jpg" alt="List of kindle dictionaries" />
                    I've been happily using my Kindle for six years with three different dictionaries. Yesterday, I wanted to add a new dictionary. How hard can this be? Well, it took longer than I want to admit. Some screenshots I found online were no longer valid… And&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/IMG_2642.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="List of kindle dictionaries" /></p>
                <p>I've been happily using my Kindle for six years with three different dictionaries. Yesterday, I wanted to add a new dictionary. How hard can this be? Well, it took longer than I want to admit. Some screenshots I found online were no longer valid…  And just a note, you do not need an active Kindle subscription to do this.</p>
<h3 id="findingthedictionarymenu">Finding the Dictionary Menu</h3>
<p>There is a <code>Settings -&gt; Device Options -&gt; Language and Dictionaries -&gt; Dictionaries</code> menu, but as far as I can tell, you can only see the dictionaries here and maybe set the default one. But to see a dictionary here, you have to first download it.</p>
<h3 id="downloadingthedictionary">Downloading the Dictionary</h3>
<p>What you actually have to do is go to the <code>Library</code> and scroll to the very bottom.</p>
<p>Does this take ages when you have a lot of books, audiobooks, and PDFs that show in the list? <strong>Yes.</strong></p>
<p>Have I found a quick way to reach the bottom other than clicking the arrow over and over again? <strong>No.</strong></p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/IMG_2639.jpg" alt="Kindle dictionary folder" width="500" height="666" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-xs.jpg 640w ,https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-sm.jpg 768w ,https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-md.jpg 1024w ,https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://blog.panvicka.com/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_2639-2xl.jpg 1920w"></figure>
<p>The second to last position is a folder named <code>Dictionaries</code>. Go inside, find the dictionary you want, and click it to download.</p>
<h3 id="usingthenewdictionary">Using the New Dictionary</h3>
<p>From this point, it should be easy to use it. Go back to your book, mark a word you want to translate, wait for the pop-up, and click on the dictionary name. You will then be able to select the new dictionary.</p>
<h3 id="anoteonux">A Note on UX</h3>
<p>The setup of the dictionaries is actually very easy when you first get your Kindle since the library is empty and the folder "Dictionaries" is right there, in your face. Let some years pass, and it will get deeper into forgetfulness. For me, it's kind of a UX fail.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
